ONKE NYATHELA

.0822282566

onkenyathela7@gmail.com · Portfolio Website · GitHub

My name is Onke Nyathela, I am currently based in Johannesburg and willing to relocate. I am 26 years old, born and bred in Dutywa, in the Eastern Cape.

I went to the University Currently known as Rhodes University and studied Computer Sciences. Upon my arrival at Rhodes, I had no understanding, nor knowledge of programming. However, the first time I started coding, it was love at first sight and I knew that I did not want to be an Astrophysicist anymore, but a Software Developer.

It is for this reason that even when I couldn't finish my degree due to financial difficulties, I continued writing code and learning new things on my own, using resources from the internet.

I have taught myself the basics of Java, JavaScript, and C++. In addition to the C#, C, and F# languages that I learned during my time at university. I am currently learning front-end development.

My current portfolio only consists of the front-end of a website and I am hoping for the opportunity to further my front-end skills and practice my back-end skills through this learnership opportunity.

EXPERIENCE

JUNE. 2018 - JULY 2019

COMPUTER SCIENCE TUTOR, RHODES UNIVERSITY

- Boosted students' understanding of Computer Sciences by reviewing classwork, homework, and practical tasks
- Utilized benchmark assessments to evaluate student progress and tutoring success.
- Promoted development of critical thinking skills and effective study habits in addition to course content

FEB 2021 – CURRENT

WEB DEVELOPER, FREELANCING

- Planning website development ideas and concepts into usable web presence with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Developing websites for individuals to help building my portfolio.
- Effectively translating client requirements into application designs and system requirements.
- Consulting with clients and providing advice of the website development.
- Effectively translating client requirements into application designs and system requirements.
- Producing functional website as finished product.

EDUCATION

FEB 2016 - JULY 2019

BSC COMPUTER SCIENCES & INFORMATION SYSTEMS, RHODES UNIVERSITY

I couldn't finish my final year due to personal reasons. Hoping to finish what's left of my modules soon.

JAN 2014 - NOV 2015
MATRIC, NOMAKA MBEKI T.S.S.S

I was able to pass with an average of 77% and with three distinctions.

FEB 2021 - MAR 2021 TEFL CERTIFICATE, TEFL FULLCIRCLE

- Teaching and learning: the principles
- Teaching skills and managing the classroom.
- Language basics

SKILLS

- HTML & CSS
- Programming: JavaScript, Java, C#, C++ and F#
- Requirements gathering
- Git and GitHub

- Technical Analysis
- Adaptability
- Effective Time Management
- Ability to Work in a Team